<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on mattstratton.io</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on mattstratton.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Matt Stratton</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 08:41:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mattstratton.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>my alfred workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/my-alfred-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 08:41:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/my-alfred-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my &amp;ldquo;must have&amp;rdquo; utilities on OS X is Alfred. Sure, Spotlight is rad and everything, but the high level of customization that Alfred provides me is deeply ingrained into my muscle memory. This is just a list of a few of the Alfred Workflows that I love, and highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/toggle-wifi&#34;&gt;Toggle Wifi&lt;/a&gt; - When my computer is in my home office, the wifi is abysmal. I like to flip it off to only use Ethernet there; this simple workflow lets me switch wifi on and off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/speedtest&#34;&gt;Speedtest&lt;/a&gt; - Like I said, my internet speed can be flaky. This performs a quick speedtest. Yes, I could run &lt;code&gt;speedtest-cli&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal, but whatever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/alfred-chrome&#34;&gt;Alfred Chrome&lt;/a&gt; - I use several Google Chrome profiles; and it never fails that the one I am trying to open the link in is the one with the wrong user. In theory this will pop a URL in the profile that I want. I&amp;rsquo;m having some issues with it now, but the idea is sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/coffeecoffee&#34;&gt;CoffeeCoffee&lt;/a&gt; - Keep your Mac from sleeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/slackfred&#34;&gt;Slackfred&lt;/a&gt; - Adds Slack functions to Alfred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/resize-image&#34;&gt;Resize Image&lt;/a&gt; - Resize an image, selected in Finder, to a target width&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/packal-updater&#34;&gt;Packal Updater&lt;/a&gt; - Update all your Alfred workflows (if they are hosted on Packal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packal.org/workflow/github-command-bar&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - Lots of helpful commands to find open issues, repos, etc, on the githubs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>danger of chef starter kit</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/danger-of-chef-starter-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 10:47:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/danger-of-chef-starter-kit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you are using the Chef Manage UI, there is the option to &amp;ldquo;Download Starter Kit&amp;rdquo;. When you do this, two things happen (which you are warned about).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your user key is reset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your organization&amp;rsquo;s default validator key is also reset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also download a pre-configured chef-repo for you, which is kind of nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the scary part. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you don&amp;rsquo;t have admin access to your organization. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to reset the validator key, which is cool, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get an error telling you that you didn&amp;rsquo;t have access to download the Starter Kit. However, unbeknownst to you, your user key was reset before this happened. So you&amp;rsquo;ve now reset your user key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story? Don&amp;rsquo;t use the Starter Kit except for the very first time you&amp;rsquo;re playing around with Chef and maybe trying things out in training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a few of my favorite things</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/a-few-of-my-favorite-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 14:21:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/a-few-of-my-favorite-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like tools and toys. There are a bunch of things I use in my day-to-day work (and play) that I&amp;rsquo;d love to share with you. hello&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RescueTime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating multiple validator keys in Chef</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/creating-multiple-validator-keys-in-chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 09:54:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/creating-multiple-validator-keys-in-chef/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;By default, many folks think that there is one (and only one) validator key for a Chef organization. Which brings up a few issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the validator key ever needs to be reset, then everyone who was using that key is screwed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the validator key is compromised, then it must be reset for everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that you can have as many validator keys as you want. For example, every user who has the capability of performing &lt;code&gt;knife bootstrap&lt;/code&gt; might have their own. Or you might use a different key for your Azure provisioning than for your VMware provisioining, etc. This is a really easy thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-validator-client-via-knife:34526d18ffb1d4e9e664c0aa33873b42&#34;&gt;Adding a validator client via knife&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;knife client create mstratton_validator_test --file mstratton_validator_test.pem --validator&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you do this, your editor will pop open which lets you make changes to the client configuration if you would like. You can use the &lt;code&gt;--disable-editing&lt;/code&gt; flag to remove this capability. The &lt;code&gt;--file&lt;/code&gt; flag will specify where you would like the private key to be written to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-validator-client-via-chef-manage-https-docs-chef-io-manage-html:34526d18ffb1d4e9e664c0aa33873b42&#34;&gt;Adding a validator client via &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.chef.io/manage.html&#34;&gt;Chef Manage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Log onto your Chef Manage UI. If you use Hosted Chef, the url is &lt;a href=&#34;http://manage.chef.io&#34;&gt;http://manage.chef.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattstratton.io/img/validator/Chef_Manage1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattstratton.io/img/validator/Chef_Manage2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattstratton.io/img/validator/Chef_Manage3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattstratton.io/img/validator/Chef_Manage4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattstratton.io/img/validator/Chef_Manage5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note - I have deleted this validator client, so don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be slick and hack the private key&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s that simple! You now have another validation client for your use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iterating through word arrays is your friend in chef</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/iterating-through-word-arrays-is-your-friend-in-chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 02:20:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/iterating-through-word-arrays-is-your-friend-in-chef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often times, when you&amp;rsquo;re installing a set of packages or Windows Features, for example, in Chef, you have a long list of items you want to install. Here&amp;rsquo;s one way to do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;package &#39;nginx&#39; do
  action :install
end

package &#39;mysql&#39; do
  action :install
end

package &#39;git&#39; do
  action :install
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty cumbersome, no? But with the magic of array iteration, we can knock this out much more simply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;%[nginx mysql git].each do |package|
  package package do
    action :install
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;%w&lt;/code&gt; portion says &amp;ldquo;split this array based on whitespace (or by &amp;lsquo;word&amp;rsquo;)&amp;rdquo;. Then for each of those items, shove the value into the variable &lt;code&gt;package&lt;/code&gt;, which we can then loop through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why a new blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstratton.io/why-a-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:04:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstratton.io/why-a-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for, um, over a decade. My oldest post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://mattstratton.com&#34;&gt;mattstratton.com&lt;/a&gt; dates back to April 1, 2001. I have literally thousands of posts over there. While quite a few of them include useful technical items, that blog has always been intended as a personal journal. Heck, it began life on &lt;a href=&#34;http://livejournal.com&#34;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt; (holla).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve been accumulating a bunch of ideas for technical posts that I would like to write up, it seemed that the old blog was the wrong place for these things. Granted, I&amp;rsquo;ve got SEO for days over there (mattstratton.com is 17 years  and 7 months old, which means the Google machine thinks I&amp;rsquo;m pretty freaking legit). But mixing in all that personal stuff, along with all the fancy-pants Wordpress nonsense, didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make a lot of sense to me. So it was time to rise from the ashes with something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered adding some blog content to &lt;a href=&#34;http://arresteddevops.com&#34;&gt;Arrested DevOps&lt;/a&gt;, but the podcast format of the site was making that challenging. And this seemed like a great chance to try out a simpler, more static-content style blog platform. So this is my experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hosting this bad boy on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. This means that I write all my posts in Markdown, and publish by using git commits (I have it hooked up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://wercker.com/&#34;&gt;Wercker&lt;/a&gt; to do the automagic posting, and you can read how to do that &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/automated-deployments/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the blog is intentionally simple right now; I&amp;rsquo;m using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nishanths/cocoa-hugo-theme&#34;&gt;cocoa theme&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably pretty it up a bit over time. But for now I want to focus on content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I&amp;rsquo;m looking to do with my Hugo experiements is to see if it&amp;rsquo;s practical to migrate Arrested DevOps over to this framework. We shall see. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a pretty complex Wordpress setup over there, and I&amp;rsquo;m loathe to mess with it too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thought - my goal with this blog is to share anything cool and useful I come accross in my travels with Chef. If I learn a neat little trick, I&amp;rsquo;ll write a blog post about it. Chance are that &lt;a href=&#34;http://jtimberman.housepub.org/&#34;&gt;Josh Timberman&lt;/a&gt; already wrote about it, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t share it with you as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>